[SPEAKER_00] For those who are listening to the recording, I forgot to start from the beginning, but we were just mentioning a few examples of hadhi from the Qur'an as the homework. So if you weren't here, I'm sorry you missed it. But inshallah, you can look for examples yourself from the Qur'an. So we were talking about the example, قُلْ هَذِهِ سَبِيلِي أَدْعُوا إِلَى اللَّهِ Allah is telling the Prophet ﷺ to say, this is the path, my path, سَبِيلِي, my path, أَدْعُوا إِلَى اللَّهِ I call towards Allah, I give da'wah, right? على بصيرة, upon knowledge, upon conviction, أنا ومن اتَّبعني Myself as well as those who follow me, meaning this is all of our path. So this tells us how important the effort of giving da'wah and calling towards Allah ﷻ is. Allah is telling the Prophet ﷺ to tell people, this is my way. If you want to talk about the way of the Prophet sallallahu alayhi wa sallam The path of the Prophet sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Very clearly Allah has signed the Prophet sallallahu alayhi wa sallam To say that this is my way Calling towards Allah That is my way Now the question comes
[SPEAKER_00] Why did Allah subhanahu wa sallam say Hadhi sabeel Right I mean there's a few understanding Meaning why is it something that's close Right We understand that sabeel is a word that's female as we mentioned Right And it's singular But why would it be considered something which is close Because it's introduced to you You're familiar with it Okay, you could say that That's a good way to explain it That it's familiar to you because The Prophet was living it and exemplifying it With his own life, so then it's as if it's right in front of you You can see it in his Exemplified in his life Others, what I've heard One explanation that was pretty nice that I've heard is that It's something which is Easy, right? It seems to be difficult But it's as if Allah is saying is hadhi it's like it's right here it's so close to you you just have to reach out and and take that path and uh it'll be easy to just to to go ahead on that path um so showing how close it is meaning it's not something which is so difficult something that you
[SPEAKER_00] will be able to do does this collate with like path and dunya because haziri was used for dunya and the path is in this dunya It's possible, but as I mentioned That we don't truly know the reasons Why the Arabs use certain words as female And certain words as male They just did And the only choice we have As we mentioned, it's Sama'i Remember we wrote this word It's Sama'i, which means It's something that you can only know through hearing It's something that the Arab used to do Most things in Arabic you could say are Qiyasi Which means that they follow A certain pattern, a certain rule But certain things you just need to know You just need to hear about it Other things you can infer based on the rule For example, we learned that If there's something which is female And you're describing it Then you add a ta'am al-boota For example, he a tabibatun So you know the word tabibun You never learned what a female doctor is But you already know the general rule That if you add the ta'am al-boota at the end It makes
[SPEAKER_00] it feminine So then automatically you're able to infer correctly That a female doctor is tabibatun However, there are certain things which you can't really guess based on the rules. It's something that you just have to know based on hearing from the Arabs or learning from a book, from a teacher. So those are things called Samari. So things like this, for example, Sabeel and Dunya, why they're female, that's just the way the Arabs use them. They use them as female words. And we don't really know the wisdom behind it. We can guess, but we will never truly know the reason behind it. Okay. Yeah, so you're saying that's why it says hadhi over there? Yeah But it could be also because at that point they're already in jahannam, right? So they're burning in jahannam So that's why it's hadhi for them Because they're literally burning in it So that's why Allah is saying hadhi jahannam This is the jahannam, the hellfire that
[SPEAKER_00] you used to deny So if there's no other examples, we can start, inshallah. We also had homework. Should we go over after? Oh, let's go over homework very quickly. Because we finished the lesson, right? Oh, very quickly, let's very quickly go over what we learned in this lesson, right? Yesterday, last lesson we learned, we already learned before that, that that marbootah is added to make, if you're describing something female, right? So for example, if you want to say وَاقِفُونَ It's somebody, a male who's standing But if you're describing a female standing, you say وَاقِفَةٌ Then we also learned a new word, اَيْضَن What does اَيْضَن mean? Also, right? Then we also learned a few words like مِكْوَاتٌ Is a new word أُخْت Yeah, good That's a new word that we learned دَرَّاجَ Is a bicycle
[SPEAKER_00] جَدِيدَةٌ We learned جَدِيدٌ So this is just a female version Mil'aqatun is a new word Spoon Qidrun is a new word which is Pot A qidr is a pot Baqara and al-falah Baqara is a cow Al-falah is Farmer Anf Nose Fem Udhun Ayn Yad Rij Yeah so all of these words They come in the Quran As we mentioned in the previous class So The rule we learned last time One was the laam Hadha li Hadha li blank Hadha li hamidin This belongs to hamid So this laam is a harful jar Is a harful jar So it makes the word That it attaches to What does it do? Makes it kasra And what is the meaning of laam? Yeah,
[SPEAKER_00] for or it belongs to So when you attach lamb to something That means you're indicating that it belongs to that person For example, you say This marker belongs to the masjid So how would you say this desk belongs to Salim? Saqeef, how would you say that? Very good, mashallah هذا المكتب This desk لسليم Is for Salim Or belongs to Salim Or another way you could say it Is through saying مُضَاف مُضَاف إِلَي Which is هذا المكتب سليم Yeah, you could
[SPEAKER_00] also say هذا المكتب سليم But certain things It's hard to say In a مُضَاف مُضَاف إِلَي format So it's easier to just add a لام And then that's the way you indicate it Right Okay, so the لام It indicates her possession And it is a harf al-jar So how many harf al-jar do we know now? Five Can somebody name them very quickly? Sorry Min, ila, and li Good So it's one of those exceptions Yeah exactly It's one of those words that Outwardly it doesn't look like it's female Because there's no But we know that it is female Because that's the way the Arabs would use it That word But there's a lot of words I mean today That's probably ten words I don't know how we can imagine
[SPEAKER_00] Once you hear it over and over again It becomes like natural Right And again Know in the Quran Focus on that in the Quran When you're reading Focus right And you'll notice a lot of these types of words Right Hadhi, sabili For example Sabil Wait that doesn't seem like a female Because there's no ta'a But the word hadhi is used So that means So automatically in your mind You'll think Okay so sabil What do you call it Is a female word So I'm not sure if you explained this last time but in the homework there's some words that we don't know okay let's just let me just finish quickly going over what we learned last lesson okay so that's another last thing we learned the lambda the harf al-jar okay then one more thing we learned is jiddan right what does jiddan mean very right so you add it to an adjective to show that something basically to emphasize something that it's very much like that right so somebody give me an example
[SPEAKER_00] Very good, mashallah Al-Taqs means the weather Or you could say Al-Jaw Either one Harun Jiddan So Har means hot We learned that in the second lesson, I think Jiddan means very, right? So the weather is very hot Very good, mashallah Any other examples? Yeah Jayidun, that's a new word Maybe you can add it to your vocab This is a good word to know means something which something is good this is good means very good got it so like in official Arab universities or schools they'll have levels right you know how we have you got an A plus or an A or a B in the test so they'll have levels like that, right? So you have average, you have jayid, you have good,
[SPEAKER_00] which is like, I think, upper 80s. Then you'll have jayid jiddan, which is, jayid un jiddan, which is like in the 90s, right? Then you'll have mumtaz, which is like the highest level, which is like probably 95 to 100, like an A+, basically. So jayid un jiddan means very good. So just emphasizing the word jiddan. Give me one more example of jiddan. Who was samin un jiddan? Okay. Right. Saminun means fat. Right. You're talking about me? No, I'm saying that. Okay. All right. So huwa saminun jiddan means he is very fat. Okay. One more example. Close. Very close. So you said hadihi ad-dajajatu? Then? Hadihi ad-dajajatu? Lazeez Lazeez Close Lazeez Lazeez Remember
[SPEAKER_00] No, remember This rule Yeah, exactly Very good هذه دجاجة لذيذة جدا because دجاجة as we learned just in today's lesson just last lesson in the homework yeah دجاجة is a chicken right it's the female it's the hen basically right and ديك is a rooster right so since it's a female and you can tell by the تامر بوط so that's why the word describing it also has to be female so you cannot say لذيذة you have to say لذيذة You get it? Sorry? Oh, they're married. Okay, so yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] So very good, right? The chicken is very good. Okay. So that's basically what we learned in the last lesson. Okay, sorry. One more important rule we learned in the last lesson. Can somebody remind me what that important rule was? It was we learned it at the end. two body parts okay good what about the two body parts like if we have yeah if we have multiple like two or more is female and singular if we have nose is singular good very good yeah yeah the general rule although there may be slight exceptions I don't know if you go into like detail and you learn like medicine in Arabic I'm sure there's probably some exceptions some like organs that we don't really think about. But generally, the rule for body parts in Arabic is that the organs that only have one part, for example, the nose, you only have one nose, right? Then mouth,
[SPEAKER_00] you only have one mouth. Those are going to be male. So you say هَذَا أَنفٌ ذَا لِكَ فَمُنٌ But those body parts that have two or more counterparts, those are going to be female. The male, I don't know if we have the two at the bottom of it. So is that male or female? Yeah, actually, that's not an exception. It actually works because the zhakar refers to that organ. And then the two are called khusyatani. So they're both female. So it works. The question, I mean, you can ask a brother after class, inshallah. Okay, so that's the general rule for body parts.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. We can go into the homework now, very quickly. Let's go through it very quickly, inshallah. We don't have, I don't want to get done quickly, inshallah. Okay, so the homework, sorry, the first homework was just iqra' waqtub, read and write. Alright, so very quickly, Brother Umar, number one, page 35 at the bottom. Yeah, no. No. If there's no reason to make it Kasra or Fathah, just keep it. Default is going to be Pesh, Dhamma. So, what was it? What would it be? Yeah, Madrasatun. The Ra has a Fathah on it. So, Madrasatun. Okay, translate it. A Masjid. Because it doesn't have L, right? This is a Masjid and this
[SPEAKER_00] is a Shafi. A school. Yeah. He said this is a Masjid and this is a school. Okay. Brother Raqib. Okay. Okay, good. Although, a more accurate translation would be this. Yeah, a more accurate translation would be this, because she would be here, right? Who is she? But who is this is different. This, obviously, when we say this in English, there's no differentiation between male and female. But we know in Arabic that we're talking about a female because you say hadihi, right? So to translate hadihi, you would say this, not she Because she is hiya That's the difference between the two words A lot of times people conflate these huwa and hadha And also hadihi and hiya So they're slightly different Although they're similar But as we mentioned in hiya, which is a dameer pronoun There's no connotation
[SPEAKER_00] of far or close It's just you're referring to someone you had mentioned earlier Whereas hadihi, it has a connotation of something which is close So anyways, continue One more time Good No, he's right Very good, sister of Abbas Very good Who is this? This is a sister of Abbas Okay, good No, it's wrong Remember, Mudaaf never ever Will never have Al or Tanween Remember that? yeah sorry how would the meaning change it says one has a tea no it's
[SPEAKER_00] not So for the professions, we learn muhandis, we learn tabib, and they change to tabibah, muhandisah. But how about filah? Falaah is not a feminine word. Falaah is not a feminine word. How would you say a male filah? No, filah is a male farmer. A female farmer would be falahatun. I wrote that as a feminine. No, so what was, in the example, it says, هَذَهِ بَقَرَةُ الْفَلَّاحِ So the Hadi is referring to the Baqara, not the Fallah. You get it? So the cow is Fima, not the Fallah. That's something to keep in mind. Okay. So continue reading. Somebody quickly. Ibrahim. Next.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Translate. This is a mooster. And this is a female chicken? Yeah, which is called? In English, what is it called? Hen? Yeah. Okay. All right. Is it dojaja or dajaja? Huh? Is it dojaja or dajaja? Dajajatun. I don't think there's any shutdown. There's no shutdown, I think. So it's dajajatun. Okay. All right. Um, Brother Abdul Wahab, next one. No, no, before that, four. We wouldn't have a daughter of a school, right?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, say it again. Good, yeah, very good, mashallah Remember he didn't say Right, why? Because it comes in the middle of a sentence So you don't pronounce it You just say It's So there's no tanwin on the ibn And al-mudir becomes kasra Ibn al-mudiri The son of the principal This is the son of the principal This is also The daughter of the teacher This is the daughter of the teacher And hadhi is used because that's female Okay I have a question about Will the second letter always be Jazm or Shadda Because there's Ibn, there's Ism, there's Al They all have Jazm as the second letter A jazm on the second letter
[SPEAKER_00] Not necessarily, I think. I can't, I can't, I have to think a little more if that's always the case. I'm not sure. Next, Abdullah. You can read it or you want to? You had a long break. Yasirin, yeah. Good. Hadhi umu yasirin. Okay, you want to translate it? This is Yasir's mother. Good, this is Yasir's mother or the mother of Yasir. No, أم ياسرين Because it's مضاف مضاف إلي Okay Let's see Harun, go ahead I can tell by the way you were looking at me That's why I called on you أين قدر الحم قدر الحم قدر الحم قدر الحم Oh, you said قدر الحم
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, there's a couple of words that we don't know here, so I'll translate it for you. أَيْنَ means Where? قِدْر means Pot اللحم means Meat. So that's a new word. اللحم means meat. Where does it come in the Qur'an for fad? Okay, what's the ayah? وَفَاكِيَةٍ مِمَّا يَتَخَيَّرُونَ وَلَحْمِ طَيْرٍ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ So Allah is talking about the bounties And the amazing blessings of Jannah And so he mentions that They will have Fakiha Special fruits that they choose From their own liking And the meat of tair Tair means birds The meat of birds From that which they desire So good There's another Good These things have been made impermissible for you Dead carcasses
[SPEAKER_00] Blood The meat of Khinzir means Pig Meat of pigs Very good So it's Masha'Allah So the lamb is part of this word Yeah, the lamb is part of the word So there's two lambs There's a lamb that's from the al And there's a lamb that's part of the word itself Which is lahm This is the first time we see He is being used for a thing Not a person Now then we used it before too Yeah we did Where is the meat of pot? The pot of meat Yeah So the pot of meat So you see how
[SPEAKER_00] Over here, remember we were talking about You can loosely translate it as Possessor and possessed But it doesn't always work, so this is an example Where it doesn't work, right Qidrul lahm means the pot of meat That makes sense when you say pot of meat When you say that the pot Owns the meat, it doesn't work Right, or sorry, the meat owns the pot It doesn't make sense, right It just means a pot That consists of meat, right So that's why it doesn't always work to say that mudaf is a possessor and that's that's why i guess i just said the easiest way to remember it especially in the beginning after some time it'll become second nature but in the beginning the easiest way to remember just put it in the form of blank of blank right once you put in that form it becomes very easy to understand you don't have to think oh who's a possessor who's a possessed just put in this format qidr means pot okay pot and then you put of, and then the second word which is lahm, which is meat pot of meat, very simple you don't have to think, oh wait, no, how does
[SPEAKER_00] that make sense because the meat doesn't own the pot, and you know, you start getting into some philosophical thing, like wait you know, how can meat own something and stuff like that, no, you don't have to do all that just blank of blank that's the easiest way to remember Allah okay al-thalaja means fridge, refrigerator okay, so al-thalaja means Refrigerator Related word which is from the same root is Thalj Thalj is snow So if you want to Now is the season of snow So if you want to talk about snow The word is Thalj Thalamjim This comes in a Hadith Or a Dua Anybody know the Dua It's a Dua that's That's mentioned very commonly Very commonly recited Dua for a dead person When somebody passes away A selj
[SPEAKER_00] I put a kasra Sorry Yeah So that's why you say Yeah Okay So Which du'as are coming Very quickly Give you 30 seconds It's like wash my clothes With my arms Very good Yeah He got the translation But the Arabic So there's a dua Sunnah dua Narrated from the Prophet When somebody passes away Right Hafiz al-Sabh always recites it Whenever somebody passes away Then there's Allahumma ghafil lahu Warhamhu wa'afihi Wa'afhu anhu Akrim nuzul lahu Wa wasi' mudkhalahu Wa ghafilu bil ma'i Wa thalji Wal barad Meaning wash him with water and snow and ice وَنَقِّهِ مِنَ الْخَطَايَةِ And do these, purify him from all his sins Just as a
[SPEAKER_00] white cloth is purified from filth So imagine a very visual image of how this person will be purified of all their sins If we're making dua for them So it's a beautiful dua Anyways, الثلج is snow And from that is Which is a refrigerator Because it causes Things to become cold Okay, so Lastly, very quickly Salim This is a door and this is a window Right here This is a door and this is a window وَهَذِهِ نَافِذَةٌ هَذَا بَابٌ وَهَذِهِ نَافِذَةٌ Okay, so nafitha is a new word. It means window. Isn't that dhal, right? That means that dhal, right? Dhal, yeah. Nafitha. Yeah. Okay. Alright. Now let's go quickly to this tamrin. This practice, right? مَهَذَا وَمَهَذِهِ Okay? So
[SPEAKER_00] that first picture, very quickly. Uthman. This is some hada for the man. Okay, good. Now first you just say which question applies to it. Does مَا هَذَا apply to it or مَا هَذِهِ apply to it? Yeah, so just say it like this. مَا هَذَا هَذَا قَلَمُ Like that, just say it like that. Okay, Brother Jibril? A spoon? Yeah. Okay, anybody else? A spoon? Yeah. مَا هَذَهِ good. What is this? It doesn't help. Good. It came in this lesson It came, we're here Page 34 in the middle Okay, next Very easy, this is like from the first page of the first lesson
[SPEAKER_00] You're too slow Okay, next Next, brother Atif? Are we on the shirt? The fourth, yeah. Ma haza? Ma haza kamizu. Good. Ma haza, haza kamizu. Good. Saqif, next one. Ma haza, haza baytum. Okay, that's literally like the first line of the first lesson. Okay, good. All right. Do you want to? What do you? Ma haza, haza sa'ad. Yeah, but you would use hadihi. Because sa'a is a female word, right? Which is anzit tamil buddha. Yeah, exactly. Because anzit tamil buddha. So you say, مَا هَذِهِ هَذِهِ سَيَّارَةٌ Good. Okay, Hamad, next one. Okay. Yeah, but then seyyara is a female word, right? Because it's ta'a at the end, tambuta. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] مَا هَذِهِ هَذِهِ سَيَّارَةٌ Okay, what is this? This is a car. Okay. What is this? This is a door Okay, I honestly don't know what he's referring I think he's referring to feet, foot, legs Rijlun, good Good, so why do you say hadhi Even though there's no tamar buta Yeah, because it's a body part that has Two counterparts to it So that's why you say hadhi Very good Okay, Uncle Shogut Good What is this? This is a bike Okay Next I think it's referring to his mouth It looks like it's referring to the beard or something But I think it's referring to his mouth Okay Brother
[SPEAKER_00] Hamza No, to the right, the picture of the mouth. Very good, mashallah. Ma hatha, hatha, famun. Right, so it's male, there's only one mouth, so you say, it's a male, so you say, I mean it's a masculine, so you say, ma hatha, hatha, famun. What is this? It's a mouth. So since it's brotherhood, hair would just be one thing for a whole body, brotherhood? Yeah, you say sha'ar. Sha'ar means hair. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So how do you pronounce it? Famun? Famun, yeah. Famun. Yeah. Okay. Brother Basu? Hafiz Basu? It's a pot. I had a... I had a... Okay, but... You fell for the trap.
[SPEAKER_00] Hadid? Remember we mentioned there's some words That They seem to be male Because they don't have But they're actually female And why is that the case Because Arabs use them like that So Qidr is one of those words So you say Brother Abdul Aleem Next one The hand No, that's that's flag Yadun Good, mashallah You say Hadhi because it's not a single organ but it has two, there's two hands, so because there's two counterparts, you use the word Hadhi It's female, okay Just to go back, heart is Qadrun, right? Yeah Yeah. Okay. All right. Brother Hansel, next one. I think he's referring to
[SPEAKER_00] the nose because it's sticking out a lot. Yeah, good. What is this? This is a nose. Okay. Good. The fridge on the right. I'll do it on the bottom right. Good, masha'Allah. Because a female, because it has tamarbootah. Okay. Who didn't go yet? Umar? Brother Umar? The key. Good, masha'Allah. What is this? This is a key. It's male, so you say. Hafizu Kasha? Good, masha'Allah. who didn't go good
[SPEAKER_00] there's two other words on top good that's perfect although maybe would probably be more accurate but anyways Uthman you didn't go here right I didn't go yet who didn't go yet iron no not you your father Very good You guys are going to be like Wait, when did we learn that? The answer is It's on the first page of this lesson At the end of the page Right Mikwatun is Iron Right Mikwatun Har Har Yeah, good mashallah Good, I like that We have to try to use these words And fit them together with other words we know And make sentences So he said
[SPEAKER_00] So I just made a slight correction It's Haratun Because Mikwat is female So Har is an adjective describing it So that's why he would say Haratun Because it has to match with the female So what was it translated to? The iron is very hot Okay, very good, mashallah All right, last one. We're going to do the last one. It's a chair. Good. What is this? This is a chair. Okay. Next. Okay. This is a very simple lesson. I'm just going to go from right to left. Okay, we're going to keep going like this. An alliance of be ready. We want to get this done in two minutes. We're going to get this lesson done. I mean, this whole exercise done. What do you do? It's very simple Based on the first line You can get the idea Read the example And make a sentence According to that example
[SPEAKER_00] So Muhammad is a student So what you're doing Is you're taking that same sentence That they made for the male And you're making it into a female form Using a female name So all you have to do is Add this tamarboota at the end of the word All you have to do in this So let's start very quickly Let's start with Hamad Hamidun Tabibun Tabibatun Tabibatun No Tabibatun Tabibatun No Yeah Tabibatun And also, it's not Fatima At-Tun What is it? Fatima At-Tu If you recall back a few lessons We learned that female names If you go to page 23 Just look at that list of names Female names
[SPEAKER_00] are always going to be They're not going to have Tanween Remember that? Female names do not have Tanween So you're not going to say Fatima At-Tun You say Fatima At-Tu Like in the hadith it says Fatima At-Tu, Sayyidat Nisa'i Ahlul Jannah Fatima is the leader of the women of Jannah So the hadith says Fatima tu It doesn't say Fatima tun It says Fatima tu Because female names have only one dhamma They don't have tanwin Generally So that's why you say Fatima tu Tabibatun So you just made that tabib and tu Tabibatun Okay, brother Very good He is a Muslim She is a Muslim Female Muslim Good Othman? Very good. Will it translate it? Good. The door is closed and the window is closed. Very good.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, good. Yeah. All right. Good catch. Okay, next, Brother Jibreel. It's a khaw, right? Wasi khun Do you remember what that means? Dirty So I'm mendeel Mendeel means? Handkerchief So transition Yeah, we just translate that first Okay, now next female Yeah, good Because Yad
[SPEAKER_00] is a female word Even though it doesn't have ta'amabuta Because it has two counterparts Okay, good So the hand is dirty Alright, so if you want to say my hand is dirty You say, my hand is dirty. Then you say, يَدِي وَسِخَةٌ Okay. Next, number six. Say that again? If you want to say, my hand is dirty, like you just said, you say, يَدِي وَسِخَةٌ You can say, the hand is dirty. But if you want to say, my hand, you say, يَدِي وَسِخَةٌ My hand is dirty. اَيْدِينَ That's plural. Let's not get there though. Let's keep it simple. Next. No. Your hand still says female, even if you're a male. You get it? Remember when we talked about the rule for the body parts? It doesn't matter about the person who owns those body parts. It doesn't matter. Every person, even the most masculine male person, their body parts will be female if they have two
[SPEAKER_00] of those body parts. Okay. If that would have been, for example, the nose, then... Yeah, it would be male. Even if it was the nose of a female, the nose would still be considered male. Do you get it? So, wait. So, if you're talking about male, Yadu was it? No, no, no. Your hand is always going to be female, no matter what. That rule we talked about, the body parts, right? It has nothing to do with the person who owns the body parts. So For a person Like for male Right Your hand Al-Yad Will always be female Right So don't look at The person who owns The body part Oh because this is the hand That's one Yeah Okay Because you talk about nose Male Even if it's the nose Of a female Your so-called An-Fun Is going to be male
[SPEAKER_00] But The Vase Vase Is still Will apply Yeah Because you're describing the hand, you're not describing the person. Do you get it? No, I'm saying instead of hand, if you put a singular body on it, that is going to be yeah, then it will be yeah, is a new word. What do you guys think it means? Jai, right? T, Asshay in Arabic. Alright? Al-Shayu Harun. Trying to say that? Al-Shayu Harun. The tea is hot. Okay. The tea is hot. Okay. And then Al-Kahwatu Harun, again, because there is no Haratun. There is. There is. There is Haratun? Yeah. Yeah. I thought it was one of those exceptions. No, no, no. Okay. Al-Kahwatu Haratun. Right? So, Brother Yasir, if you go to a Kahwa house, you can say,
[SPEAKER_00] you know, the Kahwa is hot. Right? Okay. Kahwa means coffee. Right? Okay. All right, next, Brother Hafiz Ba'aso. Okay. Good. The masjid is far and the school is far. Okay. Okay, good. Yeah, the female student is sick. Good. Uncle Shodra? Okay, Sariyar is a new word. Sari'un means quick Quick Sari'un means quick You should learn this word well Because it comes in the Quran multiple times Very good Wallahu sari'un al-hisab You've probably heard that ayah before right Many ayahs end like that Wallahu sari'un al-hisab Hisab means taking into account So Allah is swift Or quick
[SPEAKER_00] in taking into account Okay So sari'un means quick Okay Sorry, let the uncle finish No, no, you have to use the same word Very good Right? Because it's a female So the fast car So now you know how to say a fast car Okay It is a horse, yeah but we were talking about assayara yeah okay next one were the eyes the answer why you made kasra because it's it's one of the what we
[SPEAKER_00] learned law and Yeah, but that has nothing to do with making it kasra. Are you pronouncing the lamb or not? Are you saying ash-shams or al-shams? Yeah, but why are you saying ash-shamsi? Why is it kasra? Because of al. No, al does not make anything kasra. Remember, there's only two things that we learned so far That makes me kasra Somebody tell me One Harif al-jar, good And we learned five of those And then the second thing is Very good So if it's not one of these two Then you shouldn't be making it kasra for no reason Okay So, again, the default is nothing making it kasra Just keep it as Pesh or dhamma Yeah Exactly
[SPEAKER_00] Good The sun is beautiful Yeah, that's true But technically it's So it still falls under that category Okay Let's let Do it Okay, Hamza, you want to do it? The father is sitting. Next. Just make it into a female form. The mother. Good. The mother
[SPEAKER_00] is sitting Okay Okay Next Sorry 22 Can we just finish this very quickly Or should I just do it myself Okay brother Salim Quickly number one You just have to fix the mistake All you have to do is fix the mistake in this sentence Haqibatu man hadha What's the mistake here Haqibatu man hadha No Hadhi good Haqibatu man hadhi Because it's referring to the haqibah So it should be female Okay, good Next Haqif Good It should be maftoohatun So that's correcting that mistake Okay Hada sayyaratu tabib What's the mistake here? Good Hadi hi sayyaratu tabib Very good, mashallah Another one Yeah, go ahead Yeah, read it wrong first Hadi hi miftaahu sayyaratu Miftaahu sayyaratu The key of the car That's why So
[SPEAKER_00] what's the correct way to read it? Sorry? No, no Yeah, good Because Hadi is referring to the key Right? So it's incorrect Right This is the key of the car So it should be Okay, last one Who wants to do the last one? Best for last one Good. So in the book it says But they wrote it wrong on purpose for you to correct it So uncle corrected it to Which is correct, right? Because is female So it should be So that's why it's wrong to say means road as we learned I think two lessons ago Is road or street Okay And I think the rest we don't need to It's just testing if you know Just to test if you know that Lam is
[SPEAKER_00] a harf al-jar Alhamdulillahi So now we know In Surah Fatiha we say Alhamdulillahi Why is Allah's name Kasra here? Because of li Lam, right? So all praise belongs to Allah So now subhanAllah we already know We're already learning Surah Fatiha The meaning of it by ourselves We just learned this one letter And it opened that dimension up for us Okay, last one It's an ayah of the Quran So it's just testing if you know the Lam or not Alhamdulillah we finished this lesson And that's
[SPEAKER_00] all we're going to learn For a whole month After a month we're going to start learning again What was the date that we had mentioned? January 13th Yeah so first day of class when we come back January 13th and January 15th we'll be at a test So next time we have another session In which we continue this Will be The next week after that So it's going to be a while But inshallah Hopefully we all keep reviewing In the break Because again The test will be after the break So we don't want anybody to We don't want everybody To stay on their toes And not enjoy their break So We're going to Have review sessions As I mentioned again It's upcoming Monday And Wednesday So come prepared for that Inshallah If you think you don't need it Then I guess you don't have to show up But obviously I think we all Could use a review Inshallah And also those brothers, you can convey the message There were many brothers who started off But then they missed a few lessons And they feel like, oh man, I can't catch up now So if they wanted to join this session They might be able to just catch
[SPEAKER_00] up Through this lesson, inshallah So if they wanted to join, they would definitely be good to join Yeah, like right from Right from there Alright All right. Subhanallah, bihahamdihi, subhanakallah, bihahamdihi, kanashidu, la ilaha illaha talisagfiru, katuweylehi. Why is there a...